Robert H. Taylor Collection of English and American Literature, 1280s-1958 (bulk 1800s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 3: Modern Manuscripts (Unbound) and Correspondence, 1545-1969; 23 archival boxes
  - Fitzgerald, Edward, 1809-1883, 1835-1883; 4 folders
    - Correspondence II - 15 letters 1835-1883: 1 to Mr. Brooke,1 to "Mrs. Brown," 1 to Ellen C., 1 to Mr. Crabbe, 1 to Mr. Groome[?], 1 to Prof. C.E. Norton, 1 to Mr. Polarich[?], 1 to Mr. S. Rice, 2 to Smith & Elder, 1 to Mr. Spalding, 1 to W. M. Thackeray, 1 to Miss Valentin [?]," and 1 by W. Aldis Wright to George Crabbe III about Fitzgerald's death, 1 to an unidentified friend, 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence III - 8 letters to "Posh" (Joseph Fletcher) and a picture of Fletcher, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous - photograph of Fitzgerald's boat, transcribed copies of 4 letters, bookplate of Fitzgerald, "A Friend of Fitzgerald" (sheets torn from Shandygaff), sheets from "Edward Fitzgerald's Letters' by Canon Ainger; other items, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Fleming, Daniel, 1649; 1 folder
    - manuscript/small, bound notebook: "A Booke of English and Latin verses of sondry subiects" (includes one page of classical Greek at the end), 1649; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Forbes, William, Sir, 1739-1806, 1800; 1 folder
    - manuscript: "Love's Gambol, or, The Lad of Spirit," 5-act drama, Ms (in unknown hand), 90 leaves total (numbered 1-13, 1-17, 1-20, 1-17, 1-23), circa 1800; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Forster, Edward Morgan (E. M.), 1879-1970, 1939; 2 folders
    - 2 letters (1951) to "Bill"; 1 letter (1939) and 1 postcard (1962) to David Garnett ["Bunny"]; 1 photograph of (from left) W. J. H. Sprott, Gerald Heard, Forster, and Lytton Strachey, sitting at an outdoor table, inscribed on back to "Bunny, with love and best wishes for Xmas from Morgan", 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Autograph letters, manuscripts, and photographs, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - 3 letters (1941-1942) to "Mr. Connolly"; 6 pages from an unidentified piece, probably a review, 1 photograph of Forster, undated 1 photograph of Forster by William Plomer, portion of 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Fowler, John Henry, 1861-1932, undated; 2 folders
    - Correspondence I (A-H): 3 by Arthur H. D. Acland, 2 by Alfred Ainger, 1 by Percy S. Allen, 2 by William T. Arnold, 1 by W. H. Asquith, 2 by John Bailey, 2 by Ernest Barker, 2 by T. A. Barnett, 4 by Lawrence Binyon, 2 by Herbert Blakiston, 2 by John Bradbury, 7 by A. C. Bradley, 1 by James Bryce, 1 by Geoffrey Butler, 1 by Archibald Campbell, 2 by Charles Cannan, 1 by Reginald Coupland, 1 by A. T. Quiller Couch, 2 by Henry Craik, 1 by Arthur S. Cripps, 5 by H. G. Dakyns, 2 by Walter de la Mare, 5 by Aubrey de Vere, 1 by Stephen de Vere, 1 by Samuel Dill, 2 by Austin Dobson, 1 by Oliver Elton, 1 by Julia Gaskell, 2 by M. E. Gaskell, 1 by Charles Gore, 1 by William Hardie, 2 by C. Reggie S. Harris, 13 by Gordon Hewart, 2 by A. V. Houghton, and 1 by Ralph E. C. Houghton, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence II (L-W, Unknown): 1 by W. R. Lamb, 1 by Albert Liverpool, 6 by J. W. Mackail, 1 by John Masefield, 1 by David Masson, 1 by Wilfrid Meynell, 2 by C. E. Montague, 1 by T. Sturge Moore, 1 by T. W. Newman, 1 by Reginald Palgrave, 3 by Alfred V. Paton, 1 by John Percival, 2 by Louis C. Purser, 1 by Walter Raleigh, 4 by Bruce L. Richmond, 5 by R. W. [Robert?], 1 by [?] Robertson, 1 by J. Rowley, 1 by M. E. Sadler, 1 by George Sampson, 1 by Charles P. Scott, 2 by Herbert Sidebotham, 1 by John H. Skrine, 1 by [?] Smith, 1 by Arthur L. Smith, 1 by George Smith, 1 by Leslie Stephen, 1 by J. Stone, 1 by Henry D. Traill, 1 by Larisa Fulham Todd, 2 by William W. Vaughan, 2 by Glesson White, 3 by Herbert Warren, 1 by W. Wetz, 1 by J. R. Williams, 1 by J. Wilson, and 11 Unknown, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790, 1784; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to Dr. Price: 1 letter, 1784; 1 folder (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Galt, John, 1779-1839, 1837; 1 folder
    - 2 letters: 1 to his printer, 1 to the publisher of the Scottish Guardian, 1837; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 1)
  - Garrick, David, 1717-1779, 1773; 1 folder
    - six-line epigram of verse, 2 pp., undated marriage agreement, drawn up by Garrick on behalf of R. B. Sheridan, stating the conditions on which Sheridan will marry Elizabeth Ann Linley, 1773, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 2)
  - Gaskell, Elizabeth Cleghorne Stevenson, 1810-1865, 1854-1861; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1854-1861 1 to [Mr. Chapman], 1 to "Miss Kay," 1 to "Mrs. Spencer"(?), and 1 to "Dear Sir", 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 3)
  - Gay, John, 1685-1732, 1705-1713; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter and document, 1705-1713; 1 folder
      - 1 letter to Nicholas Dennis, 1705 assignment to Jacob Tonson of rights and title to Gay's "Mock Pastorals," 1713, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 4)
  - Gibbon, Edward, 1737-1794, 1783-1793; 2 folders
    - 1 letter (in French) to "Monsieur Levade", 1789; portion of 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 5)
    - [1 letter (in third person) to [Mrs. Holroyd], 1783 - MISSING?], portion of 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 5)
    - Autograph letters: 1 to [John Pinkerton], 1793 1 (in third person) to unidentified person, 1783, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 6)
  - Gibbons, Grinling, 1648-1720, 1687; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to John Evelyn, circa 1687 and 1 letter on second page of Gibbons' letter by Evelyn, circa 1687, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 7)
  - Gilbert, William Schwenck, Sir, 1836-1911, 1879-1887; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Miss Parson" regarding the opening night of The Pirates of Penzance, 1879 and 1 letter to unidentified person, 1887, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 8)
  - Godwin, William, 1756-1836, 1816-1817; 2 folders
    - Autograph letters (1803-1809): One to Charles Burney (1757–1817), and one to an unidentified person, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 9)
    - 1 memorandum of agreement for Mandeville, 1816 1 promissory note, 1817, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 10)
  - Goldsmith, Oliver, 1728-1774, 1753-1774; 1 folder
    - Autograph letters: 1 to "Mr. Nourse" [John Nourse], 1774 1 fragment to unidentified person, circa 1753, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 11)
  - Gore, Catherine Grace Frances, 1799-1861, 1841; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Mr. Webster," undated 1 partial letter, "My Patron Cardinal d'Amboise," undated; 1 ANS to Edward Moxon, undated 1 manuscript of "Lamentation of the last dandy of the season in Hyde Park. July 31st, 1841 a parody," 3 pp., 1841; and miscellaneous papers, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 12)
  - Gosse, Edmund William, Sir, 1849-1928, undated; 1 folder
    - Correspondence I: 8 letters (1897-1919) to Max Beerbohm, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 13)
  - Grant, Anne, 1755-1838, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 note to unidentified person, undated; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 14)
  - Graves, Richard, 1715-1804, 1780; 1 folder
    - 1 receipt, to Robert Dodsley, 1780; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 15)
  - Gray, Thomas, 1716-1771, 1760-1769; 3 folders
    - 1 letter to William Robinson, 1763 1 letter to Rev. James Brown, 1767, 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 16)
    - The Colour of Plants: manuscript, 1 leaf, 4 pp., circa 1760; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 17)
    - Ode: manuscript of an ode for music performed at the installation of the Duke of Grafton as Chancellor of the University of Cambridge in 17691 leaf, 4 pp., 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 18)
  - Greville, Fulke, Baron Brooke, 1554-1628, 1588-1592; 1 folder
    - 6 autograph letters to Richard Bagot, circa 1588-1592; 1 folder (Box 7a, Folder 19)
  - Grinfield, Thomas, Letter to Thomas De Quincey, 1847 February 4; AM 2017-10; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    Signed autograph letter (7 pages), partly in verse, from Bristol clergyman, poet, and hymnist Thomas Grinfield at Clifton (near Bristol) to his former Winkfield classmate Thomas De Quincey praising the publication of De Quincey's article on Landor in Tait's Magazine.
  - Hall, Samuel Carter, 1832; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to John Carne, 1832; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hamilton, Margaret, Countess of Orrery, 1738; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Revd Sir", 1738; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Harcourt, Edward, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to unidentified person, undated; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hardy, Florence Emily (1881-1937), Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1911-1933 January; 5 boxes
    Letters are arranged in chronological order.
    These very personal letters from Florence to her close friend span a lengthy period and document pivotal events in Hardy's life, specifically those relating to her relationship with Thomas Hardy. These include the death of Thomas Hardy's first wife, Emma; Florence's marriage to Thomas in 1914; and Thomas' death in 1928.
    Many of the letters concern Florence and her husband's personal lives as well as Thomas Hardy's writings and professional endeavors. Some also include discussion of current events, specifically World War I, due to the death of Thomas' cousin whom he had selected as his heir. A few photo postcards are also included, such as one that depicts Florence, Thomas, the Pococks, and other friends enjoying a picnic (May 7, 1918).
    Purchased in 2014 (AM 2014-88).
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1911; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1912; 3 folders (Folder 2-4)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1912; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1913; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1913; 2 folders (Folder 1-2)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1913; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1914; 2 folders (Folder 4-5)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1914; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1915; 2 folders (Folder 7-8)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1916; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1916; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1917; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1917; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1918; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1918; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1919 June-December; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1920; 2 folders (Folder 8-9)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, circa 1920; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1921; 2 folders (Folder 1-2)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1923 January-September; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1924; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1925; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1926 July-September; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1928; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1930; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1931; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Letters to Constance Innes Pocock, 1932-1933 January; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928, 1871-1940; 23 folders
    - 15 letters (1891-1918) and 1 document: 1 to Edmund Gosse, 1 to William Heinemann, 2 to P. Morley Horder, 1 to "M. Davray," 1 to "My dear Levinson", 1 to "Mr. Perkins," 1 to J. S. Udal, 1 to "Professor Windle," 5 to unidentified persons; 1 letter by H. A. Martin to "Mrs. Pearce" about Hardy; 1 bill for typing service, 1895; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (A1), 1871-1878; 1 folder
      - 17 letters 1871-1878: 1 to William Minto, 3 to Smith, Elder & Co., 1 to Mrs. [Genevieve] Smith, 1 to "Mr. Stephen," 11 to William Tinsley, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (A3), 1881-1892; 1 folder
      - 3 letters 1881-1892: 1 ALS to [Kegan] Paul, 2 to "Rev'd Mitchell", 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (A4), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 4 letters (1908-1909) to Rev'd Cyril P. Wix, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (A5), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 5 letters (1896-1926) to Henry Arthur Jones, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence (A6), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 7 letters (1892-1914) to John Lane, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence (A7), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 3 letters (1897-1906) to the Society for the Protection of Ancient Buildings (2 copies in wife Emma's hand), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence (A8), 1913-1916; 1 folder
      - 4 letters 1913-1916: 2 to F. A. Duneka, 1 to H. C. Duffin, 1 (carbon) by F. A. Duneka to Hardy, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence (A9), 1920; 1 folder
      - 5 letters 1920: 3 to Alfred Noyes, 2 (carbons) by Alfred Noyes, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence (A10), 1922-1927; 1 folder
      - 3 letters 1922-1927: 2 to John Lane by Florence Hardy, with lists; 1 card to "Dear Sir" by Edward Clodd, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence (A11), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 3 letters (undated-1908) to "T. Pouncy", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence (A12), 1895-1915; 1 folder
      - 12 letters 1895-1915: 11 to Clement King Shorter; 1 to Mrs. (Emma) Hardy by Shorter, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence (A13), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 7 letters (1901-1925) on the subject of the treatment of animals: 1 to Mr. Henry B. Amos, 2 to the Humanitarian League, 1 to Revd. S. Whittell Key, 1 to H. S. Salt, 1 to "Mrs. Haukey"?, 1 to "Mr. Pouncy", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence (A14), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 1 letter (1914) to Mrs. W. K. Clifford, with two 1915 photographs of Florence Hardy, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (A17), 1914-1940; 1 folder
      - 3 letters 1914-1940: 2 to Sydney Cockerell (1 draft), 1 by Cockerell, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence (A37), 1912-1924; 1 folder
      - 11 letters 1912-1924: 10 to Sydney Cockerell, 1 to Mrs. Cockerell, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence (Tinsley), 1871; 1 folder
      - 1 document and 24 letters (1870-1875) to Hardy: 21 by William Tinsley, 1 by W. Croft, 2 by the Wilts and Dorset Banking Company; 1 balance sheet for Desperate Remedies, 1871; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence (Miscellaneous), dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 23 letters (1911-1927) by Hardy: 13 letters to J. C. Squire; 6 to W. G. Lockett, 1 to "Mr. Colles," 1 to the Editor of the Daily Chronicle; 1 to Sydney Cockerell; 1 to unidentified person, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - 2 letters (1927-1928) about Hardy: 1 by Sydney Cockerell to "Bliss" [Carman], 1 by Florence Hardy to Curtis Brown, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Letters to Samuel C. Chew, with related notes: 13 letters and cards by Hardy and his wife (Florence) to professor Samuel C. Chew, chiefly about his book on Hardy, together with Hardy's notes and corrections for a new edition of it., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Letters to C. W. Saleeby: 32 letters and cards by Hardy and his wife (Florence) to C. W. Saleeby 1878-1940, doctor, eugenist and reformer, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "The Going of the Battery", 1899; 1 folder
      - autograph reworked proof of the poem "The Going of the Battery": 1 proof-page, mounted, with holograph revisions and additions, 1899; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23A)
    - Review of Poems of Rural Life in the Dorset Dialect, undated; 1 folder
      - corrected galley proofs, 7 leaves, undated; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "Saturday Night in Arcady", 1891; 1 folder
      - manuscript of the concluding three folios, nos. 11-13, of the serial version of Chapters X and XI of Tess of the D'Urbervilles, 3 pp., with several holograph revisions, 1891; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Hawker, Robert Stephen, 1859; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Doctor [William] Budd, 1859; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Hawkins, Anthony Hope, Sir, 1863-1933, 1894-1923; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1894-1923: 3 to "Mr Barr," 1 to [Michael] Sadleir; 1 note with signature, 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1804-1864, 1839-1857; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1839-1849: 1 to John O'Sullivan; 1 (note) to Louise Hawthorne (one letter by Sophia A. Hawthorne); 1 letter to Edmund P. Whipple, and Photostat of the same, 1848; 1 letter to Charles Sumner, 1849, with transcript of the same, portion of 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - 1 document signed to the Inspector of the Port, Custom House, Salem. Mass., 1848 March 20 1 document signed by Hawthorne, a voucher authorizing payment to consulate staff member, for payment of $616.43 dated 1857 December 31 autograph only on Hawthorne on a slip of paper, portion of 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Haydon, Benjamin Robert, 1786-1846, 1823-1843; 4 folders
    - 3 letters 1823-1838: 1 to James Elmer, 1 (contains sketch) to Winstanley (?), 1 to unidentified person, portion of 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 158 letters to Mary Russell Mitford (in 3 folders), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 42 letters: 1817-1822 and misc., undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Also includes signed check for ^200 to Martha Hutchins; 3 letters to Mitford's father circa 1917-1920 fragment of a pen-and-ink sketch for Haydon's oil painting, "Christ's Entry into Jerusalem"; 1 undated letter from Haydon to Mary Mitford; 1 letter (fragment, postmarked 1823) to Haydon by Mary Russell Mitford (with added sketch by Haydon?)
    - 53 letters, 1823-1825; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 64 letters, 1826-1843; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hayley, William, 1745-1820, 1785-1817; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1785-1817: 2 to Rev'd Mr. Johnston, 1 to "Mr. Cadell", 1 to "Hebe" [Mary Meyer], 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hazlitt, William, 1778-1830, 1816-1822; 1 folder
    - 3 letters 1816-1822: 1 to his printer, 1 to P. G. Patmore (lower half of page 1 in hand of Sarah Walker), 1 to Lord Cockburn by W. Hazlitt about his father, 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Henderson, Archibald, 1877-1963, undated; 1 folder
    - Correspondence, undated; 1 folder
      - 19 letters (1925-1926) to Paul Reynolds; 4 letters (1925) to Paul Reynolds about Henderson, undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903, 1901; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to D. A. Munro, 1901; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Herbert, Alan Patrick, 1890-1971, undated; 1 folder
    - manuscript of verse, "Vile Song About the Treasury," 2 pp., with 3-page draft (published in Punch in 2/1961), undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Herbert, Thomas, Sir, 1606-1682, 1835; 1 folder
    - manuscript of verse on the marriage of Lady Dorothy Hutton, 2 pp, circa 1835; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hillyer, Robert, 1895-1961, 1939; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Mr. Schoeck", 1939; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hobhouse, John Cam, 1786-1869, 1820; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to John Gardner, 1820; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11A)
  - Hogarth, William, 1697-1764, undated; 1 folder
    - Miscellaneous related material, undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hogg, James, 1770-1835, 1824-1834; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1824-1834: 1 to James Gray (with pen-and-ink drawing of Hogg by A. Croqui), 1 to James Elliot (with manuscript of poem entitled "What is Man!", 1 p., 1829), 2 to unidentified persons, 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894, 1829-1906; 1 folder
    - 9 letters 1842-1894: 1 letter to Rufus Griswold, 1842; 3 letters to "Dear Sir", 1863-4, 1867; 1 letter to Edward Pierce, 1880; 1 letter to Walter Basant and Walter Pollock, 1880; 1 letter to Mrs. Humphry Ward, 1894; 1 letter to "My Dear Warner", Sept. 13, 1894; 1 letter to an unidentified person, undated, portion of 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1 photograph of Holmes Sr., taken at Harvard, 1829 1 autographed card, 1878 2 letters of Oliver Wendell Holmes Jr.--1 letter to Lord Justice James, 1878 1 letter to William H. Fry, 1906 1 cabinet card photograph of Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr., portion of 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hood. Thomas, 1799-1845, 1827-1844; 1 folder
    - Small Collection, circa 1827-1844; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14A)
      A group of eight autograph letters signed (to various correspondents); two autograph manuscripts ("The Water-Nymph" and "Literary Reminiscences, No.1"); a fragment of an autograph letter signed; five engraved portraits; and an ephemeral item. Nearly all inlaid in folio sheets and bound with typed transcripts in limp brown calf, gilt-lettered, by Sangorski & Sutcliffe (top of spine worn); bookplates of the New York collector Alexander M. Hudnut (whose library was sold at auction in 1926) and William G. Hay. The letters are signed "T. Hood" or "Thos. Hood," except for one just signed with initials.
  - Hope, Anthony, undated; 1 item
    (see: Hawkins, Anthony Hope, Sir, 1863-1933)
  - Hopkins, Gerard Manley, 1844-1889, 1880; 1 folder
    - Manuscript of sonnet, "The Catholic Church Andromeda," 1 p., 1880; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Housman, Alfred Edward (A. E.), 1859-1936, 1896-1936; 2 folders
    - 6 letters 1896-1936: 1 to "Professor Beesly," 1 to "My dear Jackson," 1 to "Mr. Leonard," 1 to F. C. Owlett, 1 to "My dear Webb," 1 to an unidentified person (associated with a 1937 letter from Laurence Housman authenticating that the original letter was written by his brother), 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Autograph manuscript, undated; 1 folder
      - "XLIII," beginning "Her strong enchantments failing,/...," 3 stanzas, poem no. 3 in Last Poems, undated; 1 item (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Hughes, John, 1677-1720, 1717; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Lady Cowper", 1717; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Hughes, Thomas, 1822-1896, 1861-1894; 2 folders
    - 1 letter to "My dear Wilson", 1867; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Autograph letters, 1861-1894; 1 folder
      - 2 letters 1861-1894: 1 to [Mansfield] Parkyns, 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Hume, David, 1711-1776, 1757-1767; 1 folder
    - 3 letters 1757-1767: 2 to the "Marquise of Barbantane," 1 to William Strahan, 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859, 1822-1847; 2 folders
    - 1 manuscript of verse, "Beds and Bed-rooms," 1 p., circa 1847 published in Men, Women and Books ( 1847 p. 115) and 1 letter (incomplete) to unidentified person, undated, 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Autograph letter to John Hunt, 1822; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Hunt. R. N. Carew, 1930-1951; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1930-1951: 1 to "Mr. Robinson," 1 to "My dear Gavin," 1 by Cecil Lang to Hunt, 1 by Alan H. Stenning about Hunt, 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Hunt, W. Holman, 1827-1910, 1860; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Mr. Gambart", 1860; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963, 1949; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Mr. Schwartz", 1949; portion of 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - corrected TS of "Unpainted Landscape", undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Hyde and Villiers Families Poetry Collection, 1730s-1780s; 1730s-1740s; AM 2017-95; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)